<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>E-Learning on Hareesh Kanchanepally</title><link>http://localhost:1313/categories/e-learning/</link><description>Recent content in E-Learning on Hareesh Kanchanepally</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/e-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Learning Management Systems: Failure and Scope for Improvement</title><link>http://localhost:1313/notes/2011/07/2011-07-09-learning-management-systems-failure-and-scope-for-improvement/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/2011/07/2011-07-09-learning-management-systems-failure-and-scope-for-improvement/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In the light of arguments in the blogosphere and e-Learning industry that Learning Management Systems (LMS) are now ‘dead’ (Pontefract.D., 2009 and 2010; Martin Weller, 2007; Ed Cohen, 2010,et al.) and have been superseded by Personal Learning Networks (PLNs) or even Open Learning Networks (OLNs), the key focus of this post is to understand why LMS failed to meet its (early) expectations. The post first briefly defines LMS - explaining its origins, describing how it has been used, and elucidating the changing face of technology and learning theory.  It will then consider LMS’s failure to meet these changing needs, discusses the shifts to Personal Learning Networks, before finally listing some potential improvements that, if implemented, could provide a basis for repositioning LMS applications to achieve future success.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Exploration and Critique of the Arguments in Support of Using Twitter for Learning (An Essay)</title><link>http://localhost:1313/notes/2011/02/2011-02-26-twitter-for-learning/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/2011/02/2011-02-26-twitter-for-learning/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Tim Berners-Lee, while talking at the MIT Technology Review Emerging Technologies conference, recalled that, when he set out to develop the Web during 1990s, he envisioned a technology that could serve as ‘a collaborative medium, a place where we can all play; a place where can all meet, read and write’ (2004). Since the origination of the Mosaic Web browser in 1993 and the evolution of World Wide Web with the incremental features it gathered over the following years, which Tim O’Reilly cumulatively termed as Web 2.0 (Tim O’Reilly, 2005), Tim Berners-Lee’s vision of a collaborative medium became a reality. The Web has been ‘transformed from a static information medium to worldwide communication platform’ (Martin Ebner, Conrad Lienhardt, Matthias Rohs and Iris Meyer, 2010, pp. 92). The new affordances of Web that allowed users to contribute in ways of writing, posting photographs and videos, editing the existing information, building connections and making friends, etc, resulted in its rapid growth. For example, at the time of this writing, BlogPulse(2011) identified more than 154 million blogs, Facebook(2011) has more than 500 million active users, and Wikipedia(2011) is ebbing with 9.25 million articles in 250 languages. This growth in Web usage, the immediate dissemination of information, and manifold connections resulted in the so-called ‘network society’, a society whose social structure is made of networks powered by microelectronic-based information and communication technologies (Castells, M. 2004, pg. 4). The businesses took the advantage of these networked societies and went global, transforming the industrial economies into those based on knowledge and information. Eventually, this had direct and immediate impact on the&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>