<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Categories/Ed Tech on Hareesh Kanchanepally</title><link>http://localhost:1313/categories/ed-tech/</link><description>Recent content in Categories/Ed Tech on Hareesh Kanchanepally</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/ed-tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Not Just Learners</title><link>http://localhost:1313/notes/2011/01/2011-01-01-not-just-learners/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/2011/01/2011-01-01-not-just-learners/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Whether it is behavioral perspective (stimuli and response), cognitive ideology (organization or reorganization of concepts), or situative perspective (getting adjusted to the &amp;lsquo;constraints&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;affordances&amp;rsquo; of social systems), learning primarily involves a constant interplay between the individual and the environment the individual is part of. Individual is always within a context and learns out of or because of it. We are not talking of the needs that trigger learning, which might be entirely personal, but of the resources that facilitate learning. &lt;a href="http://content.karger.com/ProdukteDB/produkte.asp?doi=94368&amp;amp;hl=1&amp;amp;q=Brigid%20Barron"&gt;Brigid Barron&lt;/a&gt;, an Asst. Prof. of Education at Stanford, while providing a learning ecology framework, graphically explains how technological development in learners is influenced by different contexts. The following image is inspired by (to be candid, drives a lot of content from) her presentation. However, the image below is not constrained only to learning  new technology. People learn from different sources irrespective of the subject. Though most of the contexts presented in the image are self-explanatory, &amp;lsquo;distributed resources&amp;rsquo; refer to books, articles, on-line communities, etc. And, these contexts are dynamic. Borders of each of the context might get blurred quite often and they might intersect with the others. However, the point here is that an individual interacts with these different resources when there is a need for knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>