<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Strategic-Execution on Hareesh Kanchanepally</title><link>http://localhost:1313/categories/strategic-execution/</link><description>Recent content in Strategic-Execution on Hareesh Kanchanepally</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/strategic-execution/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Managing T/Programme Managers</title><link>http://localhost:1313/notes/2024/01/2024-01-21-managing-t-programme-managers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/2024/01/2024-01-21-managing-t-programme-managers/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;What expectations would you set to manage your team of (Technical) Programme or Project Managers effectively?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://hareesh.co/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/pexels-photo-3184398.jpeg"&gt;











&lt;figure class=""&gt;

 
 
 
 &lt;div class="img-container" style="--w: 1880; --h: 1218;"&gt;
 &lt;img loading="lazy" alt="" src="http://localhost:1313/notes/2024/01/2024-01-21-managing-t-programme-managers/images/pexels-photo-3184398.jpeg" width="1880" height="1218"&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 
 

 
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo by fauxels on &lt;a href="https://www.pexels.com/photo/people-taking-group-picture-3184398/"&gt;Pexels.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intro - Management by Exception&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Micromanagement can stifle creativity and hinder progress. On the other hand, not supporting Programme Managers in effectively executing technical programmes and projects pro-actively could result in heavy losses. Over the last decade of managing technical programmes and managers, I developed a set of expectations building on the &lt;strong&gt;Management by Exception&lt;/strong&gt; (MBE) principles. Embracing this philosophy for technical programme managers (T/PgMs) can empower them with clear expectations and autonomy, intervening only when necessary. This document outlines the &amp;ldquo;absolute musts&amp;rdquo; for T/PgMs using the MBE framework, with measurable tolerances and proactive measures to guide their actions and your monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Navigating the Spectrum of Collaboration in Product Development (Building on John Cutler's Insights)</title><link>http://localhost:1313/notes/2024/01/2024-01-06-navigating-the-spectrum-of-collaboration-in-product-development-building-on-john-cutlers-insights/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/2024/01/2024-01-06-navigating-the-spectrum-of-collaboration-in-product-development-building-on-john-cutlers-insights/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;John Cutler&amp;rsquo;s insightful ideas on convergence modes (&lt;a href="https://cutlefish.substack.com/p/tbm-261-dependencies-in-faster-growing"&gt;Part 1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://cutlefish.substack.com/p/tbm-262-dependencies-in-faster-growing"&gt;Part 2&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://cutlefish.substack.com/p/tbm-264-dependencies-in-faster-growing?utm_source=profile&amp;amp;utm_medium=reader2"&gt;Part 3&lt;/a&gt;) in product development especially in handling dependencies effectively, offered a helpful perspective for understanding how collaboration styles affect project outcomes. John proposes four different modes/ways of working: Fully Embedded, Collaborative, Supportive, Transactional. And suggests that, to “make dependency management easier, you should ask yourself: &amp;ldquo;What type of working model SHOULD we use for this work?&amp;rdquo;. This struck a chord with me. In the past few years, especially in 2023, I personally experimented with two modes for two different projects: one project that integrated different skillsets into a single, unified, cross-functional, and fully embedded team, and the other that relied on transactional ways of working supported by a framework of project management processes. Based on this personal experience, I asked myself a question: if you decide on a particular mode of convergence at the outset of a project, do the different phases require a dynamic shift between full immersion and focused transactional interactions?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Art of Launching a Tech Program: My 15-Year Playbook</title><link>http://localhost:1313/notes/2023/04/2023-04-12-the-art-of-launching-a-tech-program-my-15-year-playbook/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/2023/04/2023-04-12-the-art-of-launching-a-tech-program-my-15-year-playbook/</guid><description>&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://hareesh.co/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/spot-runs-start-la.jpg"&gt;











&lt;figure class=""&gt;

 
 
 
 &lt;div class="img-container" style="--w: 1880; --h: 1255;"&gt;
 &lt;img loading="lazy" alt="" src="http://localhost:1313/notes/2023/04/2023-04-12-the-art-of-launching-a-tech-program-my-15-year-playbook/images/spot-runs-start-la.jpg" width="1880" height="1255"&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 
 

 
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo by Pixabay on &lt;a href="https://www.pexels.com/photo/athletes-running-on-track-and-field-oval-in-grayscale-photography-34514/"&gt;Pexels.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fifteen years ago, a simple question from my boss ignited a flame that still burns bright: &amp;ldquo;Can you make this idea fly?&amp;rdquo; That &amp;ldquo;idea&amp;rdquo; became my first foray into the exhilarating world of technical program management (TPM), a journey that has since woven its way through over 40 tech projects and a dozen intricate, multi-team programs. From nimble startups to sprawling enterprises, I&amp;rsquo;ve learned that while contexts may differ, the bedrock of success lies in a meticulous &amp;ldquo;set-up&amp;rdquo; phase. This isn&amp;rsquo;t a rigid checklist, but rather a playbook honed through experience, designed to de-risk delivery and unlock early learning. So, gather around, fellow journeymen, and let&amp;rsquo;s delve into the secrets that unlock high-flying tech programs.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Employing System Thinking to Technical Programme Management</title><link>http://localhost:1313/notes/2023/03/2023-03-13-employing-system-thinking-to-technical-programme-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/2023/03/2023-03-13-employing-system-thinking-to-technical-programme-management/</guid><description>&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://hareesh.co/wp-content/uploads/2024/01/pexels-photo-1472612.jpeg"&gt;











&lt;figure class=""&gt;

 
 
 
 &lt;div class="img-container" style="--w: 1880; --h: 1253;"&gt;
 &lt;img loading="lazy" alt="" src="http://localhost:1313/notes/2023/03/2023-03-13-employing-system-thinking-to-technical-programme-management/images/pexels-photo-1472612.jpeg" width="1880" height="1253"&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 
 

 
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photo by Lina Mamone on &lt;a href="https://www.pexels.com/photo/lighted-city-during-night-1472612/"&gt;Pexels.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Embarking on the integration of WeChat Pay for our Chinese customers was not just a project; it was a riveting exploration of dependencies, interconnections, and the intricate dance of technology in a dynamic ecosystem. This journey demanded more than conventional project management—it required a masterclass in systems thinking. In this playbook, we unravel the saga and distil the lessons learned into actionable insights for fellow technology program managers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>